<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Seastar</title>
    <link>http://seastar.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Seastar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 08:02:27 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://seastar.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seastar Framework Accepted for Google Summer of Code</title>
      <link>http://seastar.io/blog/2018/02/seastar-framework-accepted-for-google-summer-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 08:02:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seastar.io/blog/2018/02/seastar-framework-accepted-for-google-summer-of-code/</guid>
      <description>Seastar Framework Accepted for Google Summer of Code By: Raphael Carvalho.
Interested in contributing code to a framework that provides ScyllaDB and other programs with high-throughput I/O and networking? The Scylla team is pleased to announce that Seastar framework has been accepted as a Google Summer of Code organization. Google summer of code with the Seastar project provides students with the opportunity to spend their summer break contributing to an awesome open source project, work under the mentorship of dedicated, brilliant engineers, and in addition receiving a stipend when the project milestones are met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seastar: The future&lt;&gt; is Here</title>
      <link>http://seastar.io/blog/2018/02/seastar-the-future-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 08:02:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seastar.io/blog/2018/02/seastar-the-future-is-here/</guid>
      <description>By Alexander Gallego
This is a cross-post from Alexander&amp;rsquo;s Blog.
On June 8, 2016, Avi Kivity came to NYC to present ScyllaDB. During his search for a quick open desk to do some work, I volunteered open spaces we had at Concord1. We talked lock-free algorithms, memory reclamation techniques, threading models, Concord and distributed streaming engines, even C vs C++. Five hours later I was convinced that Seastar was the best systems framework I’d ever come across.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>